(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-28T20:21:59.714472",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
近づいている
Drawing near,
冬の足音
the footsteps of winter.
耳を澄ませば
If you strain your ears,
聞こえる鈴の音
you can hear the sound of bells.
寝ぼけた頭に響く目覚ましを
An alarm clock ringing in my sleepy head,
手さぐりで止めたあと雪の気配
stopped blindly, then a hint of snow.
始まりを告げるすてきな季節が
A wonderful season announcing the start—
happy holidays, happy holidays
What a glorious time of year!
すやすやと眠る子供達の手に
Into the hands of children sleeping soundly,
抱かれたテディベアももう待ちきれない
the hugged teddy bear can no longer wait.
クリスマスが今年もやって来る
Christmas is coming again this year,
悲しかった出来事を消し去るように
as if erasing all the sad things that happened.
さあ パジャマを脱いだら出かけよう
Come on, take off your pajamas and let's go out,
少しずつ白くなる街路樹を駆け抜けて
running past the street trees turning white little by little.
華やぎ始めた街は急ぎ足
The city starting to bustle is in a hurry
贈り物決まる頃黄昏れてく
As gifts are decided, dusk falls
かじかんだ指をママが温めるね
Mom warms my numb fingers
Happy holidays, happy holidays what a glorious time of year!
大切なものはみんなそばにある
What is precious is right beside everyone
穏やかな毎日が続く贅沢に
The luxury of peaceful days continuing
クリスマスがもうじきやって来る
Christmas is coming soon
うれしさをかくせない犬や猫まで
Even dogs and cats can't hide their joy
もみの木に灯る明かりをうけて
Taking in the light shining on the fir tree
いつもよりやさしそうなパパの目が笑ってる
Dad's eyes are smiling, looking kinder than usual
クリスマスは誰にもやって来る
Christmas comes to everyone
もしひとりぼっちでも寂しがらずに
Even if you're all alone, don't feel lonely
心に住むサンタに呼びかけて
Call out to the Santa living in your heart
幼い頃の夢を思い出してごらんよ
Try remembering the dreams of your childhood
クリスマスが今年もやって来る
Christmas is coming again this year
悲しかった出来事を消し去るように
As if erasing sad events away
さあパジャマを脱いだから出かけよう
Now, let's take off our pajamas and go out
少しずつ白くなる街路樹を駆け抜けて
Running past the street trees turning white one by one
Happy happy holidays
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は
Ah, the town like a whipped cake
好き!雪!本気Magic
Suki! Yuki! Honki Magic
空がくれるコンフェッティは
The confetti given by the sky
冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ Woo
Is angel wings celebrating winter's festa Woo
白銀の国へ出かけるの Go Go Go
Going out to the silver-white land Go Go Go
雪の汽車が街を駆け Choo Choo Choo
The snow train runs through the town Choo Choo Choo
絵本みたいな景色を君に見せてあげるから
I'll show you a scenery like a picture book
願い込めて呪文さあ(さあ)唱えて(さんはい)
Put your wishes into a spell, come on chant it
ABCDドシジララシシ マジカルミラククル Pop!
ABCD doshijirarashishi Magical miracle-cle Pop!
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は
Ah, the town like a whipped cake
好き!雪!本気 Magic
Suki! Yuki! Honki Magic
空がくれるコンフェッティは
The confetti given by the sky
冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ
Is angel wings celebrating winter's festa
Light Upしたオーロラ色の街は
The aurora-colored town lit up
好き!雪!本気 Magic
Suki! Yuki! Honki Magic
子供でいられたら Dream Land
If I could stay a child, Dream Land
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Snow Miko!
ツンと冷たい季節が好き Love Love Love
I love the brisk, cold season Love Love Love
アイスも魔法もとけないように ヒューヒューヒュー
So that neither ice nor magic melts, hu-hu-hu
ずっとこのままじゃダメなの? やっぱりドキドキしたいな
Must it stay like this forever? I still want my heart to race
未来求め呪文今(なう)唱えて(さんはい)
Seeking the future, chant the spell now (one, two, three)
1234水金地火木マジカルミラククル Pop!
1234 Mercury, Venus, Earth, Mars, Magical miracle-cle Pop!
Ah ホップしたウサギのような気分
Ah, feeling like a hopped rabbit
好き!雪!本気 Magic
Suki! Yuki! Honki Magic
大地がくれる元気得たら 思い通り明日を生きていけるよ
If I get the energy given by the earth, I can live tomorrow just as I wish
まぶしい白に染まるハート君に
To you whose heart is dyed in dazzling white
好き!雪!本気 Magic
Suki! Yuki! Honki Magic
大人のふうなんていいじゃん
Playing the adult is fine just as it is
I hear that beat from town
The cute angel will come down
This is my home I'll let you know NAMARA fantastic!
The snowscape is lyrical The street gonna be magical
I'll set you free in my land oh oh oh oh
I'll set you free in my land, oh oh oh
今日の寒さも忘れるように (忘れちゃって)
To forget today's cold (just forget it)
悩みだって 悩みだって 凍らせて
Freeze away all our worries and troubles
消せる魔力よ (もっかい)
A magic power that can erase them (once more!)
ABCDドシラシマジカルミクルクルPop!
ABCD, do-si-la-shi, magical mikuru-kuru Pop!
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は
Ah, the town looks like a whipped cake,
好き！雪！本気Magic
Love it! Snow! Earnest Magic!
空がくれるコンフェッティは
The confetti falling from the sky
冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ
Are angel feathers celebrating winter's fest.
Light Upしたオーロラ色の街は
The lit-up, aurora-colored town,
好き！雪！本気Magic
Love it! Snow! Earnest Magic!
子供でいられたら Dream Land
If I could stay a child, it's Dream Land.
いいじゃん！
That's great!
弱気で流したジングル
A jingle played with hesitation,
いつもドキドキだね第一声 (にゃはろ〜！)
Always pounding with nervousness on the first note (Nyahalo~!)
震えた声も ノートの文字も
Both the trembling voice and the notebook text,
みんなみんな手繋いでGO！
Everyone holding hands, let's go!
弱気で流したジングル
A jingle played with hesitation,
いつもドキドキだね第一声 (にゃはろ〜！)
Always pounding with nervousness on the first note (Nyahalo~!)
震えた声も ノートの文字も
Both the trembling voice and the notebook text,
みんなみんな手繋いでGO！
Everyone holding hands, let's go!
(変わってるねって) そうなんだ
(You've changed, they say) That's right.
(なんて言ったの？) まあいっか
(What did you say?) Oh well.
飲み込んじゃってきた言葉も
Even the words I swallowed down
君と笑った声で ほら咲いて (ばんざい！)
Bloom now with the voice I laughed with you (Banzai!)
こんな私でも (もーまんたい)
Even someone like me (No problem!)
好きだって ねぇほんと？ (冗談？) 分かりそう？ (どっち？) わかんない！(本当は？)
You love me? Really? (Just kidding?) Can you tell? (Which?) I don't know! (Really?)
さくらんぼメッセージ
Cherry blossom message,
受け取って いっせーのせで！
Catch it all together, ready, set!
きっともっと キュンとしちゃうような
Something that'll make your heart flutter even more,
さくらんぼメッセージ つぼみにぎゅっと詰め込んで！
Cherry blossom message, packed tight into a bud!
君の前では私らしくいていいよね？
In front of you, it's okay to be myself, right?
(なんて返そっか 没頭！)
(What should I reply? Obsession!)
頭が(フットー！)
(My head is boiling!)
素直が(モットー！)
(Honesty is my motto!)
ゲームの中なら (Get you!)
Inside the game (Get you!)
攻略(しょっちゅう？) 百発(百中！) なのにね
Strategy (All the time?) Dead center! Yet...
どったんばったん踊ったなら
If I dance around frantically,
悩んじゃってブギウギ！
Worrying and doing the boogie-woogie!
ハートズキュンバキュン スタートボタン押せるかな？
Heart's beating fast, can I push the start button?
(ちゃんと行ったっけ？) どーだっけ？
(Did I say it right?) How was it?
(言わなきゃよかった？) そーだっけ
(Shouldn't I have said it?) That's right.
抑え込んじゃって また焼きもち
Holding it in and getting jealous again.
あー私なんて しゃがみそうになって
Ah, someone like me, about to squat down,
(訂正！) これが私だもん (大賛成！)
(Correction!) This is who I am (Fully agree!)
行くよって (右？) 曲がっちゃう？ (左？) 迷っちゃう！ まっすぐ！
Here I go! (Right?) Turning? (Left?) Getting lost! Straight ahead!
春めいて 舞って 飛び立って！
Feel the spring, dance, and take flight!
そっとじっとシュンしちゃう日も
Even on days when I quietly feel down,
さくらんぼメッセージ 瞳にぱっと映るよ！
Cherry blossom message, reflecting brightly in your eyes!
背中を押してメロディー
A melody that pushes me forward,
好きでいていいよね？
It's okay to keep loving you, right?
誰かじゃなくて 君がいいって
Not just anyone, I want it to be you.
(絶対！) 何度でも言うよ (もう一回！)
(Definitely!) I'll say it as many times as it takes (Once more!)
好きだって ねぇほんと？ (冗談？) 分かりそう？ (どっち？) わかんない！ (本当だ！)
You love me? Really? (Just kidding?) Can you tell? (Which?) I don't know! (Really!)
さくらんぼメッセージ 受け取って いっせーのせで！
Cherry blossom message, catch it all together, ready, set!
きっともっと キュンとしちゃうような
Something that'll make your heart flutter even more,
さくらんぼメッセージ つぼみにぎゅっと詰め込んで！
Cherry blossom message, packed tight into a bud!
君の前では私らしくいていいよね？ 好きでいて いいよね？
In front of you, it's okay to be myself, right? It's okay to keep loving you, right?
にゃはろー！
Nyahalo!
てんくぅ…あ、てんくるアイドルクリスマスさくらみか 新春お披露目ライブに来てくれてどうもありがとうございます！
Tinku... ah, Tinkle Idol Christmas Sakura Miko New Year Unveiling Live, thank you so much for coming!
そしてみんな メリークリスマス！イェーイ！
And everyone, Merry Christmas! Yay!
え、本日クリスマスはなんと みこちゃんのホロライブ加入記念日でもあります！おめでとう！ありがとう！ありがとう！
Um, today's Christmas is also Miko-chan's Hololive joining anniversary! Congratulations! Thank you! Thank you!
そして お披露目したこちらの衣装は 200万人記念で作らせていただいた 新春のルームウェア…ルームウェア衣装となっております！
And the outfit unveiled here is the New Year room wear... room wear outfit made for her 2 million subscriber milestone!
かわいいでしょ？
Isn't it cute?
あのね、まあいつも新衣装で悩んでるんですけど
You know, I'm always stressing over new outfits, but
作りたいなってずっと持っててたんだけどなかなかね、
I've always wanted to make it for so long,
踏み切れなかったこのルームウェアをね、200万人記念で作らしてもらいました！
but couldn't quite take the plunge. So I got to make this room wear for my 2-million-subscriber milestone!
いいアイデアだよね、これね。
Good idea, right? Right?
そして、ちょっと見ていただくんですけど、こちらじゃじゃーん！
And, let's take a look at this—Tada!
ヘアバンド！これミコピーのヘアバンドになってます。
A headband! This is a Mikopi headband.
ちょっとふあふあしてるかわいいし。
It's super fluffy and cute.
ま、このピンもいっぱい付いてて、イヤリングもかわいくってえー。
And there are lots of hair pins, and the earrings are so cute, um—
あとこのサクランボになってるんですよ、めちゃネックレスかわいい。
And it's shaped like cherries, the necklace is super cute.
でこのね、ダボッとした
And this, baggy...
ニットね、
knit cardigan,
まちょっとセクシーなね、ちょっとセクシーな
is a bit sexy... a bit sexy...
ルームウェアなんですけどね、あのちょっとなかなかね、みこちゃんはおへそを見せないんですけど、
It's room wear, but you know... Miko-chan usually doesn't show her belly button, but
おへそがね、見えまーす！
my belly button is visible!
ちょっとあの若干、ま、ね、寒くなるとね、食べたくなって若干プリってる気もしなくもないけど、
And you know, when it gets cold, I want to eat, so it feels slightly pudgy, but
まあまあまあま、気にした巻ぎですからね。大丈夫、健康的な範囲だからね。大丈夫大丈夫。
Well, whatever, it's fine! It's within a healthy range, so it's fine, fine.
ということで、あのね、隅々までちょっと見ていただきたいんですが、がー！
So yeah, I want you to check out every little detail, but—!
もっとね、見ていただきたいところがあります。見て、この
There's even more I want you to see. Look at this
お部屋、かわいいい！
room, it's so cute!
本日のライブはなんとホリバルコンさんにね、制作をあの、お願いしまして作ってまーす！
Today's live, I actually asked Holibalcon to produce it, and they made it!
本当にどうもありがとうございます！めっちゃかわいいの。
Thank you so much! It's super cute.
もう本当にね、ミコピーとかね、このソファーとかね、めちゃくちゃ細かく作っていただいたおります。
Really, things like Mikopi, and this sofa, they made them in such incredible detail.
この後もね、ちょっとね、びっくりするギミックとかもありますのでお楽しみに！
After this, there are also some surprising gimmicks, so look forward to it!
じゃあね、あ、そうだ、ハッシュタグだ！ハッシュタグは、えーこちら、
And then, oh right, hashtag! The hashtag is, um, here,
あのさくらみこ新衣装クリスマスライブでね、応援してください！スクショもたくさん撮ってね。
Please support it with #SakuraMikoNewOutfitXmasLIVE! Take lots of screenshots too.
ちょっとスクショタイム。はい。
Time for screenshots. Ready?
キュルルン！
Kyururun!
あ、かわいい！
Ah, cute!
Ah, so cute!
ということでね、みんなたくさん撮ったよね？はい、お願いします。そう。
So everyone took lots of pictures, right? Yes, please. Yeah.
そして、なんと最後に重大告知もありますので、最後までぜひお見逃しなく！ありがとうございます！よろしくね。
And, there's even a major announcement at the very end, so please don't miss it till the end! Thank you! Please look forward to it.
それでは次の曲いきますか！こちらにね、お移動させていただきまして、はい。
Well then, shall we go to the next song? Moving over here, yes.
それでは次の曲行くぞー！
Well then, let's go to the next song!
半端ないぱっぱらっぱらっぱら（はい）
Half-hearted pa-pa-ra-pa-ra-pa (Hey!)
限界突破っぱっぱらっぱらっぱら（はい）
Breaking limits pa-pa-ra-pa-ra-pa (Hey!)
毎日半端ないぱっぱらっぱらっぱら（はい）
Everyday half-hearted pa-pa-ra-pa-ra-pa (Hey!)
限界突破っぱっぱらっぱらっぱら（はい）
Breaking limits pa-pa-ra-pa-ra-pa (Hey!)
明日の私に幸あれ
May tomorrow bring me happiness
最適温度 uh 過ぎるゴースト
Optimal temperature, uh, passing ghosts
八百万の 嫌な外の要素
Eight million annoying external factors
何気ないと 超あっけらかんと
Casual and super carefree
悪気もなく邪魔するどっかの誰かさんにバイバイ
Saying bye-bye to whoever innocently gets in the way
自分時間 堕落タイム確保 17時〜9時は死守マスト
Securing me-time and slack-off time, 5 PM to 9 AM is a must-defend
さらに愛や恋や甘い蜜も忘れずに
Plus love, romance, and sweet honey without forgetting
とどのつまり オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよって注意喚起もしてますよ
Ultimately, "overwork is off-limits," I'm even putting out warnings
ねぇ楽しくて苦しくって生きてくって難しいな
Say, living life both happily and painfully is so tough
だって「安定」「裏技」「一夜漬け」甘い蜜には罠がある
Because in "stability," "shortcuts," and "cramming," sweet honey hides traps
やっ！
Yay!
眠くなったら寝る
Sleep when I'm sleepy
お昼過ぎに起きる
Wake up past noon
遊びたくて遊ぶ
Play because I want to play
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
Eat when I'm hungry
嬉しかったら笑う
Laugh when I'm happy
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
Isn't it okay to cry when I'm sad?
明日の私のために今日もなんとか頑張るのさ
Today I'll somehow do my best for my tomorrow
明日もう頑張らなくていいように頑張るのさ
Doing my best today so I don't have to tomorrow
怠惰じゃないや これ多分そうだい なんでやるやることやっています！
It's not laziness, yeah, probably so. Doing whatever needs to be done!
WHAT? & BUT 誰に知られなくても別にいいから
WHAT? & BUT It doesn't matter if nobody knows
私には私のマイルール 明日ラクするためにはハイチーズ 意外とこんな感じでラブアンドピースな毎日を生きたいのです
I have my own my-rules. Saying cheese to make tomorrow easy. Surprisingly, living every day like this with love and peace.
Don't be Don't be Don't be shy ドキドキしときたい
Don't be Don't be Don't be shy, I want my heart to race
Let Let Let me shine 明日天気になれ
Let Let Let me shine, may tomorrow be sunny
To To To be excite 心もっと踊りたい
To To To be excite, I want my heart to dance more
Sunday Monday Tuesday Wednesday 木金土日月
Sunday Monday Tuesday Wednesday, Thu Fri Sat Sun Mon
辛くなったら歌う
Sing when things get tough
むかついたら愚痴る
Complain when I'm pissed
やりたいようにやる
Do as I want
それができたら苦労しないわ
If that were easy, I wouldn't struggle
常に一喜一憂
Always fluctuating in joy and sorrow
頼むから 適当にセーブし服を回避しつつまあ頑張るのさ
Please, do your best while dodging unnecessary risks!
適当に今日までは言うまいがまあ頑張るのさ
Even if things are half-assed till today, I'll somehow do my best!
夢の中では… ずっとぐったらしてやるんだ
In my dreams... I'm gonna laze around forever.
誰かのためとかそんなんじゃない明日の私のため (Fight)
Not for anyone else, but for tomorrow's me (Fight!)
楽するために苦しいことも乗り越えちゃうんだからね (Fight)
I'll get through the hard times just to take it easy later, you know (Fight!)
やりたくないことやらないためにやりたくないことやれ (Fight)
Do what you don't want to do so you don't have to do it (Fight!)
あれ? これって結構頑張れてる? 私とっても偉いんじゃないか! (Fight)
Wait, am I actually working hard? Aren't I just amazing?! (Fight!)
自分時間 堕落タイム確保 17時〜9時は死守マスト
Securing my "me time" and sloth time, 5 PM to 9 AM is a must-defend!
さらに愛や恋や甘いものも忘れずに
And don't forget love, romance, and sweets!
とどのつまり オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよって注意喚起もしてますよ
In short, overwork is off-limits, I'm giving you a warning!
ねえ楽してくなくして生きてくって難しいな
Man, living a life without any hardships is so tough...
だって「安定」「裏技」「一夜漬け」甘い蜜には罠がある (やっ!)
Because "stability," "shortcuts," and "cramming" have traps in their sweet nectar! (Yat!)
眠くなったら寝る
Sleep when you're tired,
お昼過ぎに起きる
Wake up past noon,
遊びたくて遊ぶ
Play whenever you want to play,
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
Eat when you're hungry.
嬉しかったら笑う
Laugh when you're happy,
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
Cry when you're sad, that's totally fine!
明日の私のために今日もなんとか頑張るのさ
Somehow I'll do my best today for tomorrow's me.
明日もう頑張らなくていいように頑張るのさ
Working hard today so I don't have to tomorrow!
半端ないぱっぱらっぱっぱらっ (はい)
Unstoppable pa-pa-ra-pa-pa (Hey!)
限界突破らっぱっぱらっぱっぱらっ (はい)
Breaking limits ra-pa-ra-pa-pa-pa (Hey!)
毎日半端ないぱっぱらっぱっぱらっ (はい)
Every day unstoppable pa-pa-ra-pa-pa (Hey!)
限界突破らっぱっぱらっぱっぱらっ
Breaking limits ra-pa-ra-pa-pa-pa
ねえあたし知ってるよ きみがひとり“XX”してるの知ってるよ
Hey, you know what? I know you're all alone doing "XX".
ピクンピクン震えてさ 声もダダ漏れなんだわ
Twitching and trembling, your voice is leaking out completely.
正直に言っちゃえよ バレてんだし言っちゃえよ 効いてんの?
Just come clean, you've been caught so just admit it, is it working?
普通普通恥ずかしい? みんな隠しているだけ もっと
Normal, normal, embarrassed? Everyone's just hiding it...
ねえあたし知ってるよ きみがひとり“涙”してるの知ってるよ
Hey, you know what? I know you're all alone crying "tears".
グスングスン凹んでさ 弱音ヒトカラ in the night
Sniffling and depressed, singing lonely karaoke in the night.
朝が来るまで一緒コース もっと泣いたって 何度だって受け止めてあげる
Staying together till morning, cry as much as you want, I'll catch you every time!
もう我慢しないで出してね MWAH!
Don't hold back anymore, let it all out, MWAH!
お願い きみが欲しいの
Please, I want you so much.
慰めさせて シェイクシェイク愛の才能で
Let me comfort you with shake-shake love talent!
泣いてくれなきゃ 溺れてしまう 濡れていたいい
If you don't cry, I'll drown, I want to stay soaked!
ねえいいでしょう? 舐め取って飲み干したいんだってば
Hey, isn't that fine? I want to lick it up and drink you dry!
お願い きみが欲しいの
Please, I want you so much.
頼り散らして シックラブ なんて最高ね
Lean on me completely, sick love is the best!
分けてくれなきゃ 君の“痛い”感じていたい
If you don't share, I want to feel your "pain".
ねえいいでしょう? 吸い取って 救いたいんだってば
Hey, isn't that fine? I want to absorb it and save you!
ねえあたし知ってるよ きみがひとり悔しがってんの知ってるよ
Hey, you know what? I know you're all alone feeling frustrated.
ズクンズクン高まるじゃん さみを推すことをやめない
Thumping and surging, you'll never stop supporting Sami!
ねえあたし知ってるよ きみはできる子知ってるよ
Hey, you know what? I know you're capable.
つらい時は 泣いとらいで ちょうどいい あたし1人でも好きだよ
When it's tough, crying is just right, I love you even if you're all alone!
お願い きみが欲しいの
Please, I want you so much.
名前を呼んでよ いつだって 会いに参上
Call my name, anytime I'll come to see you!
きみはひとりだ だから歌う「ひとりじゃない」
You are alone, that's why I sing "you're not alone".
もういいでしょう ソロプレイはおしまいなんだってば
Enough is enough, solo play is over!
きみが病めるときも あたし側にいるわ
Even when you fall ill, I'll be right by your side.
いつも見守っているわ そうよ怖くないのよ
I'm always watching over you, that's right, you don't have to be scared.
お願い きみが欲しいの
Please, I want you so much.
慰めさせて シェイクシェイク 愛の才能で
Let me comfort you with shake-shake love talent!
泣いてくれなきゃ 溺れてしまう 濡れていたいい
If you don't cry, I'll drown, I want to stay soaked!
ねえいいでしょう? 舐め取って 飲み干したいんだってば
Hey, isn't that fine? I want to lick it up and drink you dry!
お願い きみが欲しいの
Please, I want you so much.
頼り散らして シックラブ なんて最高ね
Lean on me completely, sick love is the best!
分けてくれなきゃ 君の“痛い”感じていたい 喘いでいたい
If you don't share, I want to feel your "pain", I want to hear you pant!
吸い取って 救いたいんだってば
I want to absorb it and save you!
ねえあたし知ってるよ きみがひとり“暖”してるの知ってるよ
Hey, you know what? I know you're all alone keeping warm.
グスングスン凹んでさ 弱音ヒトカラ in the night
Sniffling and depressed, singing lonely karaoke in the night.
朝が来るまで一緒コース もっと泣いたって 何度だって受け止めてあげる
Staying together till morning, cry as much as you want, I'll catch you every time!
もう我慢しないで出してね さあ
Don't hold back anymore, let it out, now!
ずーっといっしょ！
Together forever!
充電器を貸して！ またあなたのせいであたしすり減った
Lend me a charger! Once again, because of you, I'm worn out.
終電見逃して またあたしのせいで帰れなくなった
Missed the last train... Once again, because of me, I couldn't go home.
繋がってようね、消耗戦に持ち込んで
Let's stay connected, dragging each other into a war of attrition.
お互いに足を引っ張ったアオハル 沈殿した思い出でずぅっといっしょ！
Our youth, where we dragged each other down. Together forever in sunken memories!
参観日にだって 誰からも見られていない気がしたんだ
Even on parent-teacher day, I felt like nobody was looking at me.
散々シニカって 昼の街に期待しないようにしたんだ
Being completely cynical, I tried not to expect anything from the city.
そうやって守った孤独さえめちゃくちゃになった
Even the solitude I protected that way became a complete mess.
あたしだって死にたくて仕方ない こんな顔だいなしにしたいと思えないもん
I want to die so badly too. I can't bear to ruin a face like this.
共に過ごした日々が ささやかな幸せがかけがえのないトラウマになってたらいいな
I hope the days we spent together, the modest happiness, became an irreplaceable trauma.
はなればなれなんて誰かが吐かせたバグだよね？
Being separated is just a bug someone forced upon us, right?
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll stay by your side as your lifelong regret.
Q. 大切なものって、なあに？ A. 今失くしたそれ
Q. What is precious to you? A. The thing I just lost.
あたしと間違いを犯しちゃったんだ 取り返しがつかないね
You committed a mistake with me. There's no turning back now.
健やかなるときも病めるときも グロイ履歴の中で
In health and in sickness, amidst a gruesome history.
ずぅっといっしょ！
Together forever!
もうちょっとふつうに 悲しいこと悲しいと思いたかった
I wanted to calmly think of sad things as simply sad.
長調のチューンに 感情委託して楽になりたかった
I wanted to entrust my emotions to a major tune and feel at ease.
「せいぜい一生懸命に生きてくださいね」
"Please live your life to the absolute fullest."
あたしだって死にたくて仕方ない あんな歌の言いなりになりたくないの
I want to die so badly too. I don't want to become a slave to songs like that.
あなただけひとりで あたしの目を盗んで 幸せになろうなんて思わないで
Don't you dare think of finding happiness all by yourself, stealing glances behind my back.
髪を乾かしてくれた夜から あたしは壊されたんだよ
Ever since that night you dried my hair, I was broken.
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll stay by your side as your lifelong regret.
外れなくなってしまった指輪みたいに 何度もずっとフラッシュバックしてる、最低だよ
Like a ring that won't come off, I keep flashing back over and over—it's the worst.
一緒に居た時の方があたし可愛かったなあ
I was so much cuter back when we were together.
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll stay by your side as your lifelong regret.
Q. 大切なものって、なあに？ A. 今失くしたそれ
Q. What is precious to you? A. The thing I just lost.
あたしと間違いを犯しちゃったんだ 取り返しがつかないね
You committed a mistake with me. There's no turning back now.
健やかなるときも病めるときも 他の誰かと眠っていても
In health and in sickness, even while sleeping with someone else,
お揃いの悪夢でずぅっといっしょ！
Sharing the same nightmare, together forever!
天天天地獄国
[Title: Tenten Tengoku Jigokukoku]
天天天天天天天天天天天天国地獄地獄々 Open Sesame!
Heaven, heaven... Heaven and hell, hell, hell, Open Sesame!
闇と光の交わる fanatic
A fanatic where darkness and light intersect.
今宵味わう psychedelic
A psychedelic taste tonight.
踊り絡まり合う zodiac
A zodiac of intertwined dancing.
恋の駆け引きの tie-break
A tie-break in the game of love.
飾らない 存在 ただ気を惹きたい
An unadorned existence, I just want to catch your eye.
夢見心地 触れ合い 惑わせたい
Trance-like touch, I want to bewilder you.
曖昧 溶けない cocktail は甘い
An ambiguous, undissolving cocktail is sweet.
鮮やかな赤い eye 見つめて限界
Staring at the limit with vivid red eyes.
月夜に誘われ 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔が
Lured by the moonlit night, angels and demons, angels and demons...
僕(たま)さか接した 天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の
Accidentally touching heaven and hell, heaven and hell...
狭間に出会った 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔が
Meeting in the gap, angels and demons, angels and demons...
集って踊れば 天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の 門が開く
Gather and dance, and the gates of heaven and hell will open.
闇と光の交わる fanatic
A fanatic where darkness and light intersect.
今宵味わう psychedelic
A psychedelic taste tonight.
踊り絡まり合う zodiac
A zodiac of intertwined dancing.
恋の駆け引きの tie-break
A tie-break in the game of love.
Dead Alive Dead Alive Death Death Death Birth Birth Birth
Dead Alive Dead Alive Death Death Birth Death Birth Death Birth
生きた魂を tray に置いて
Placing a living soul on a tray,
めくる5枚の card 揺れる炎
Flipping five cards by the flickering flame.
先にあなたが raise したなら もう迷わない glass 飲み干して
If you raise first, I won't hesitate anymore, drain the glass.
今夜 All-in 降りない この勝負
All-in tonight, I'm not backing down from this match.
いま、天国と地獄をつなぐ門が開いてゆく 天使と悪魔、死者と生者が入り乱れ、踊り、笑い、
Now, the gates connecting heaven and hell are opening. Angels and demons mingle...
すべては混沌の中に飲み込まれてゆく。
Everything is swallowed up into chaos.
それは世界の終焉であり、
It is the end of the world,
新たなる始まりでもあるのだった。
and also a new beginning.
Dead Alive
Death Death Death
Birth Birth Birth
Dead Alive
Death Death
Birth Birth
Death Birth Death Birth Death
天 天 天 天 天 天国 天
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heavenly heaven
天 天 天 天 天 天国 地獄
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heavenly hell
天 天 天 天 天 天国 天
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heavenly heaven
天 天 天 天 天 天国 地獄
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heavenly hell
月夜に誘われ 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔が
Led by the moonlit night, angels and devils, angels and devils...
偶然交差した 天国 地獄の
Crossover by chance, of heaven and hell,
懊悩消えない 果てない moon-night
Endless agony, endless moon-night
天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の
Of heaven and hell, of heaven and hell
狭間に出会った 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔が
Meeting in the gap, angels and devils, angels and devils...
集って踊れば 天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の
Gathering and dancing, heaven and hell, heaven and hell
狭間に出会った 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔が
Meeting in the gap, angels and devils, angels and devils...
集って踊れば dance dance dance dance
Gathering and dancing, dance, dance, dance, dance
天 天 天 天 天 天国 天
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heavenly heaven
天 天 天 天 天 天国 地獄
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heavenly hell
天 天 天 天 天 天国 天
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heavenly heaven
天 天 天 天 天 天国 地獄
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heavenly hell
回想中熱くなりお茶いかが？冷静に大人で
It's getting hot in retrospect. How about some tea? Calm down, adult-like.
ハートは君にまだ教えずにご相談チラチラと
Without telling you my heart yet, glancing over to consult.
余裕 身に付けて言う「お相手はYou?」
Saying with composure, "Is the partner you?"
ドラマのようなことしない女優
An actress who doesn't do things like in dramas.
噛めば噛むほど美味しいLady例に甘え方を見せてほしい
The more you chew, the more delicious. Show me how a lady acts spoiled.
はみ出したい ん～変われないの 自由型のいい子は好き放題
I want to stand out, hmm, I can't change. A free-spirited good girl does whatever she pleases.
その塩梅 も～わからないの 優しいふりしてただ焦ってる
I don't even know that balance anymore. Acting sweet while just panicking.
要求はさりげなくお茶濁し嬉しさををごまかし
Casually obfuscating requests, masking happiness.
反省会駆け引きを学びたい 裏技をつらつらと
Wanting to learn negotiation from debriefs, stringing together secret tricks.
至急きっかけのキュー！慌ててもCute そんな事なんて仕立てないIQ
Urgent cue! Cute even when panicked. IQ that doesn't manufacture such things.
あの手この手も出来ないLady例におとし方まとめてほしい
I want you to summarize how to fall for a lady who can't use any tricks.
遠慮して ん～はしゃげないの まるっと上手くリードしたいけど
Holding back, hmm, can't make a fuss. Wanting to lead smoothly overall, but
そのボーダー も～超えないの そもそも話まだ隠してる
Not crossing that border anymore. Still hiding the main story.
(読めない 読めない)恋は
(Can't read, can't read) Love is...
(読めない 読めない)そっと口上げ君を…魅せ君を…
(Can't read, can't read) Gently lifting your mouth, fascinating you...
(包み包み)そっと心タップ 君を…ぁぁ君を
(Wrapped) Gently tapping heart, you... ah, you
(包み包み)知りたい
(Wrapped) Want to know
はみ出したい ん～変われないの 自由型のいい子は好き放題
I want to stand out, hmm, I can't change. A free-spirited good girl does whatever she pleases.
その塩梅 も～わからないの 優しいふりしてただ焦ってる
I don't even know that balance anymore. Acting sweet while just panicking.
もっと ん～はしゃげないの
More, hmm, can't make a fuss.
まるっと上手くリードしたいけど
I want to lead everything skillfully, but
そのボーダーも〜超えられないの
I can't even cross that border, hmm.
そもそも話まだ隠して 見つめてる
In the first place, I'm still hiding it and watching you.
Snow halation
不思議だね いまの気持ち
It's strange, this feeling I have right now.
空から降ってきたみたい
It's almost as if it came falling down from the sky.
特別な季節の色が とめきを見せるよ
The color of this special season excites my heart.
初めて出会った時から
From the first time we met,
予感に騒ぐ心のmelody
The melody of my heart has shouted a sign.
とめられないとまらない なぜ
I can't stop, I won't stop, why?
届けて 切なさには
Reach! To this heartrending pain
名前をつけようか “Snow halation”
Shall I name it “Snow halation”?
想いが重なるまで待てずに悔しいけど好きって純情
I can't wait for thoughts to pile up, it's vexing, but my pure devotion says I love you.
微熱の中ためらってもダメだね
Even amidst a slight fever I can't hesitate.
飛び込む勇気に賛成 まもなくStart!!
Accepting the courage to dive in, coming soon, Start!!
音もなく気配もなく
Without a sound, without an indication,
静かに運命は変わる
Fate changes silently.
これからの未来に胸の鼓動が早くなる
My heartbeat quickens to the future starting now.
例えば困った時にはすぐ駆けつけて抱きしめたくて
When you feel worried, I'll come running right away wanting to hug you tightly,
どこにいてもどこでもFly high
Wherever you are, no matter where, fly high!
急いでいつの間にか
Hurry up! Before I knew it,
大きくなりすぎた“True emotion”
My “True emotion” had grown so large.
夢だけでみてる様じゃつらいよ恋人は君って言いたい
It's painful only seeing it as a dream! The one I want to call my lover is you.
優しい目がとまどってるイヤだよ
I hate how your gentle eyes are bewildered.
このまま一気に愛情 あずけてPlease!!
Take all my affection as it is all at once, please!!
届けて 切なさには
Reach! To this heartrending pain
名前を つけようか “Snow halation”
Shall I name it “Snow halation”?
想いが重なるまで待てずに悔しいけど好きって純情
I can't wait for thoughts to pile up, it's vexing, but my pure devotion says I love you.
微熱の中ためらってもダメだね
Even amidst a slight fever I can't hesitate.
飛び込む勇気に賛成 まもなくStart!!
Accepting the courage to dive in, coming soon, Start!!
はーい！
Hi there!
みんな楽しんでくれてますかー？
Are you all having fun?
ゲストもね、たくさん来てってくださいました！みんなありがとー！
We had lots of guests come too! Thank you everyone!
そして、見てくださーい！
And look at this!
ステージもちょっとね、ぐるっと回転して、外にやってきました！すごくないですかー？
The stage turned around a bit and we came outside! Isn't it amazing?
ちょっとイルミネーションもね、きれいだねー。もうクリスマスって感じでちょっと、もうちょっと若干はら寒いけどねー。
The illuminations are so pretty too. It feels like Christmas, though it's a little chilly!
もうすごいきれいだよね、見て！すごーい！すごーい！わあー！
It's so pretty, look! Amazing! Amazing! Wow!
と、ま、ありがとうございます！
Um, well, thank you so much!
そして、なんと次で最後の曲になるんですが、
And surprisingly, our next song will be the last one,
なんと、次の曲は新曲でーす！すごーい！
but actually, the next song is a brand new track! Awesome!
ねこちゃん、ファーストアルバム以来のね、ソロの新曲となります！
It's my first solo new song since the first album, Neko-chan!
え、ソロライブを経て、みこがまた新たな一歩を踏み出す曲となっております！
Um, after my solo live, it's a song where Miko takes a new step forward!
それでは、聞いてくださーい！先ほどね、アイドル！
So please listen! Sakihokore... Idol!
アイドルだから挑み続けるんだ
Because I'm an idol, I'll keep challenging myself,
君と夢見るんだ
dreaming with you.
不器用で悪いか
Is it bad to be clumsy?
咲き誇るよ
I'll bloom proudly.
初のイベント需要無しデフォ
First event, zero demand by default,
そんな私が夢を見ました
that's the kind of me who had a dream.
アイドルという生き方
The way of life called an idol,
憧れて
yearning for it.
「無敵エリート」「笑顔はチート」
"Invincible Elite," "Smiles are a cheat,"
こんな私を見てくれる君
you who look at someone like me—
好きなとこはどこですか？
what is your favorite part about me?
わがままを許して
Forgive my selfishness.
ステージ経験値 涙滲んで
Stage experience, tears welling up,
それでも絶対負けたくない
still, I absolutely don't want to lose.
桜にメッセージ乗せて届け
Carrying my message on cherry blossoms, delivering it—
愛で溢れますように
may it overflow with love.
アイドルだから挑み続けるんだ
Because I'm an idol, I'll keep challenging myself,
君と夢見るんだ
dreaming with you.
不器用で悪いか
Is it bad to be clumsy?
咲き誇れ 妄想だけじゃ終わらせない 私らしく 桜色 ね♡
Bloom proudly! I won't let it end as mere fantasy, staying true to myself in cherry blossom pink, okay?
磨いたスキル 実力発揮
Polished skills, showing my true strength,
楽しめる日も増えてきたんだ
days I can truly enjoy have increased.
アイドルとして生きてる
Living as an idol,
君のおかげ
all thanks to you.
アホ毛はキュート！勝ち確ルート！
Ahoge is cute! Guaranteed win route!
そんな私についてきてよね！
Be sure to follow a me like this!
ドジなとこも許されて
Even my clumsy sides are forgiven—
最強じゃん！
aren't I the strongest?!
痛いの言いたいのにグッと飲み込んで
Wanting to voice the pain, but swallowing it back,
笑顔で笑顔増やしたいな
I want to increase smiles with a smile.
桜前線が君の町に 春を届けるように
Just as the cherry blossom front brings spring to your town,
アイドルだけは
an idol alone—
譲りたくないんだ 君に見せたいんだ 理想へ挑むよ
I don't want to yield, I want to show you, I'll challenge my ideals.
駆け抜けろ
Run through!
最高景色見せたげる 信じていいよ 桜を
I'll show you the highest scenery, you can believe in the cherry blossoms,
さあ 皆で咲かそう 満開のピンクで世界染めて
come on, let's make them bloom together, dyeing the world in full-bloom pink.
ああ この涙はね
Ah, these tears...
悲しい方じゃないから安心して
aren't from sadness, so rest assured.
きれいだね
How pretty.
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol,
挑み続けるんだ 君と夢見るんだ
I'll keep challenging myself, dreaming with you.
不器用で悪いか
Is it bad to be clumsy?
咲き誇れ 妄想だけじゃ終わらせない
Bloom proudly! I won't let it end as mere fantasy,
私らしく 桜色 ね♡
staying true to myself in cherry blossom pink, okay?
みんな！ピンクライドルクリスマス新衣装ヒロメライヴを見てくれてどうもありがとう！
Everyone! Thank you so much for watching the Pink Idol Christmas New Outfit Unveiling Live!
ここで告知が3つあります！
Here are three announcements to make!
まずは、こちら！
First is this!
200万人記念ルームウェア衣装お披露目記念グッズが発売されます！
The 2 Million Subscribers Commemorative Room Wear Outfit Unveiling Commemorative Goods are on sale!
きみじゃるはオルダン先生に描いてもらいました！いつもありがとうございます！
Kimijaru was drawn by Orudan-sensei! Thank you always!
イラストのテーマはお部屋でノンビリしているみこです！
The theme of the illustration is Miko relaxing in her room!
それでは、1つずつ見ていきましょう！
Now then, let's look at them one by one!
まずは、こちら！
First is this:
リバーシブルブランケット！
Reversible Blanket!
おもてにはみこぴ、うらにはみこの大きなイラストが描いてあります！
The front features Mikopi, and the back has a large illustration of Miko!
まあるく包まれると、みんながみこぴのぬいぐるみになっちゃうよ！
When you wrap yourself up in it, everyone becomes a Mikopi plushie!
続いて、みことおそろい35Pヘアバンド！
Next, the Miko-matching 35P Hairband!
みこの新衣装とおそろいのヘアバンドです！毎日使いができるアイテムです！使ってね！
A hairband matching Miko's new outfit that you can use every day! Please use it!
次わ、みこと愛用35Pマグカップ！
Next is Miko's favorite 35P Mug!
お耳もついているマグカップなんだよ！ついに再現できました！
A mug with cute little ears! We were finally able to recreate it!
飲み物を入れてもよし、小物入れにするもよし！素敵なのちタイムのおともに使ってね！
Great for drinks or small items! Use it alongside your wonderful home time!
最後はルームウェアみこちの35Pぎゅっ♡おねんねぬいぐるみ！
Last is the Room Wear Mikochi 35P Huggable Nap Plushie!
ルームウェア衣装のみこがぬいぐるみになりました！みんなも一緒にお休みしようね！
Miko in her room wear outfit has become a plushie. Let's all rest together!
フルセットはこんな感じです！
The full set looks like this!
そしてそして、フルセット特典はポストカードです！
And the full set bonus is a postcard!
今回は箱押しの複製サインとメッセージ付きになっております！
This time featuring a foil-stamped signature and message!
みんな、ぜひぜひ購入してくださいね！
Everyone, please make sure to purchase it!
告知2つ目は、こちら！
The second announcement is this!
本日初披露した新曲咲き誇れアイドルが本日21時から配信開始！
The newly premiered song "Sakihokore Idol" releases today at 21:00!
ファーストソロライヴを終えて次のステージに向かっていく気持ちをカニワークさんに書き下ろしていただきました！
Kani-waku-san wrote this to capture the feelings moving toward the next stage!
そしてそして、この後先ほほらアイドルのMVがプレミア公開となります！とっても可愛いのでみんなたくさん聞いて見てくださいね！
And right after, the MV for "Sakihokore Idol" premieres! Please check it out!
告知3つ目は、こちら！
The third announcement is this!
なんと！さくらみこ×鳴門鯛焼本舗のコラボが2026年に決定しました！なんと4回目ですよ！
Sakura Miko x Naruto Taiyaki Honpo collaboration for 2026 has been decided! For the 4th time!
今回開催期間は2026年2月20日から3月31日までです！やったー！
The event will run from February 20 to March 31, 2026! Yay!
本当にね、こんなに長く続いているのはみんなのおかげでもありますし、鳴門鯛焼本舗さん本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much to everyone for keeping it going for so long, and to Naruto Taiyaki Honpo!
詳細情報は後日またXなどで告知するので楽しみに待っていてくださいね！
We'll share more details on X later, so please look forward to it!
今日は本当にありがとう！みんな、メリークリスマス！おつみこでした！バイバーイ！
Thank you so much today! Everyone, Merry Christmas! Good Miko! Bye-bye!